Isaias Ponce

isaiasponce-12@hotmail.es Ecuador Guayaquil +593968913869 LinkedIn: isaias-ponce-569109104

Software Developer

Resume Summary

Developer with over 4 years of experience and a C1 level in English, specializing in remote work and possessing extensive knowledge in web development and backend technologies. Proficient in implementing CI/CD using agile methodologies such as SCRUM and XP, with a focus on efficiency and user-centered design.

Work Experience

Software Engineer, TeduEmprende, Eloy Alfaro, Guayas, Ecuador 07/2023 - Present (3 months)

- Currently working in a temporary contract, focusing on diverse software development tasks and responsibilities.
- Stack: Php, Laravel, Hostinger, MariaDB, React.js, Bootstrap, jQuery, JS, HTML5, CSS, Moodle y Pagosmedios.

Full Stack Developer, Arkho, Chile (Remote)

01/2023 - 07/2023 (7 months)

- In charge of the backend development of the characterization module of the project for the Chilean government.
- Achieved a 40% increase in data processing efficiency and backend responsiveness using AWS, Kubernetes, and PostgreSQL.
- Integrated services for a notification engine (SMS, Whatsapp, Email) using **Reactjs**.
- Unit testing using **Unittest** with **Python**.
- Specialized in various technologies including AWS, Kubernetes, Amazon S3, Docker, PostgreSQL, and React.js.

Full-Stack Developer, Plataforma Gescolar, Guayas, Ecuador 07/2019 - 11/2022 (3 years 5 months)

- Developed the User Interface and facilitated seamless interactions with the backend system.
- Acquired and applied skills in Amazon Web Services (AWS), React.is, and Python.

IT Tester in Application/Software Department, Huawei Latinoamérica, Guayaquil, Guayas, Ecuador (Internship Contract) 01/2021 - 08/2021 (8 months)

- Conducted software testing and provided support to corporate customers.
- Engaged in troubleshooting with colleagues, focusing on understanding business logic, and stayed abreast of the customer's new requirements.

Education

Telematic Engineer, ESPOL, Guayaquil, Ecuador

03/2021

- Degree in Telematic Engineering (Software Engineering + Telecommunications)
- Thesis: Traceability of agricultural products using blockchain (Python, Flask, HTML/CSS/JS, Internet of Things (IoT))

Skills

- Languages:
 - English (C1 Advanced Level)
- Web Development:
 - Laravel, React.js, Next.js, NodeJS, ExpressJS
 - HTML/CSS/Bootstrap
- Programming Languages:
 - Python, Java, JavaScript, C
- Cloud Services:
 - AWS (Lambda, API Gateway, DynamoDB, Cognito, S3, AWS CDK)
- Database Management:
 - Oracle PLSQL
- Methodologies:
 - SCRUM and XP
- Soft Skill:
 - Empathy
- Tools:
 - VScode, Git, Linux, Postman, Pycharm

Certifications

- AWS Cloud Practitioner: Certified by AWS
- CCNA 200-301: Certified by Cisco
- Google IT Automation with Python: Professional Certificate
- Google IT Support: Professional Certificate
- Automating Real-World Tasks with Python
- Configuration Management and the Cloud